<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://basliqlabs.github.io/qwest-docs/blog</id>
    <title>Qwest Docs Blog</title>
    <updated>2024-07-28T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://basliqlabs.github.io/qwest-docs/blog"/>
    <subtitle>Qwest Docs Blog</subtitle>
    <icon>https://basliqlabs.github.io/qwest-docs/img/favicon.ico</icon>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Qwest Was Created?]]></title>
        <id>https://basliqlabs.github.io/qwest-docs/blog/why-qwest-was-created</id>
        <link href="https://basliqlabs.github.io/qwest-docs/blog/why-qwest-was-created"/>
        <updated>2024-07-28T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this blog post I am going to explain why I created Qwest.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In this blog post I am going to explain why I created <code>Qwest</code>.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-real-reason">The Real Reason<a href="https://basliqlabs.github.io/qwest-docs/blog/why-qwest-was-created#the-real-reason" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to The Real Reason" title="Direct link to The Real Reason">​</a></h2>
<p>I like <strong>challenges</strong>.
That is the main reason why I started this project. "The idea of developing a software from scratch sounds fun to me, why not make it good enough so other people would benefit from it?" is the thought that is constantly in my mind. I also like the project management field and concepts, so why not make a project management tool then?</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="impact">Impact<a href="https://basliqlabs.github.io/qwest-docs/blog/why-qwest-was-created#impact" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Impact" title="Direct link to Impact">​</a></h2>
<p>I mean we code every day but most of us can't see the direct impact of our pull-requests on the clients and customers, can we?<br>
<!-- -->I really want to create a piece of software that people could actually use and tweet about it saying "this thing really helped me out, kudos to whoever made this possible".
In this situation, that feeling that someone has noticed your work, and you have been useful to humanity is just sweet.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="merging-university-projects">Merging University Projects<a href="https://basliqlabs.github.io/qwest-docs/blog/why-qwest-was-created#merging-university-projects" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Merging University Projects" title="Direct link to Merging University Projects">​</a></h2>
<p>Right now that I am starting this project (2024-07-28), I am a CE student in <code>Azad university: Tabriz branch</code> and as a student I had to work on assignments and projects for each course. (No I don't ChatGPT things)</p>
<p>So I said to myself, <em>what would happen if instead of doing 10 meaningless small projects I did this one big project</em>?</p>
<p>To which I responded with <em>hmm, that's actually not a bad idea</em>.
I talked with my professors to see if they approve this idea which they did and here we are.</p>
<p>List of courses that helped Qwest grow into the beautiful software that she is now:</p>
<ul>
<li>System analysis and design (prof. Karimi, sem 4)</li>
<li>Software Engineering (prof. Karimi, sem 5)</li>
<li>Database Design (prof. Pirahesh, sem 7)</li>
</ul>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="testing-stuff-out-in-basliq-labs">Testing Stuff Out in Basliq Labs<a href="https://basliqlabs.github.io/qwest-docs/blog/why-qwest-was-created#testing-stuff-out-in-basliq-labs" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Testing Stuff Out in Basliq Labs" title="Direct link to Testing Stuff Out in Basliq Labs">​</a></h2>
<p>I am trying to find a way to think about system design, write backend code, try new frontend frameworks out (there are literally new frameworks out every week in the JS community, isn't that just cool?), get familiar with AI, and grow some vegetation in GitHub. Testing different things out is the main reason why I add <code>Labs</code> to the end of <code>Basliq</code>.</p>
<p>The best way is starting my own project because no one uses <code>PWA</code>s or <code>Svelte</code> here in Iran because every company is so busy surviving the economic crisis they miss the real point of software development which is to have fun using the latest and shiniest tools out there in the wild and then <code>shift+del</code>ing the project because these tools are no longer supported :( Sorrowful indeed.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="possible-future-side-hustle">Possible Future Side-Hustle<a href="https://basliqlabs.github.io/qwest-docs/blog/why-qwest-was-created#possible-future-side-hustle" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Possible Future Side-Hustle" title="Direct link to Possible Future Side-Hustle">​</a></h2>
<p>Classic capitalism using marketplaces.
If I sold project management panacea for 5 dollars, wouldn't everybody be willing to purchase it?😈</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Ata!</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/atareversei</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="qwest" term="qwest"/>
    </entry>
</feed>